Sebastian, why are Bayes Nets important?
&gt;&gt; They're one of the most amazing
accomplishments of recent artificial
intelligence.
They take the idea of uncertainty and
probability and
marry it with efficient structures.
So you don't have a big mumble jumble
but you can really understand,
like what uncertain variable
influences other uncertain variable.
A theory of the world using just
Bayes Networks is really an amazing.
&gt;&gt; Well, I've been teaching AI for
many years, I've found that listening to
Sebastian's lessons has really given
me a better intuition for Bayes Nets.
As you go through these lessons,
make sure to understand how to construct
a Bayes Nets and
how to do inference with them.
One of my favorite algorithms
is Monte Carlo Markov Chain.
Have fun with the lesson.