We have tried the same trick as before,
where we use exact same prior
of first plus gives
the following factors, 0.9, 0.2.
But our minus gives us
the probability 0.1 for
a negative test result
treatment of cancer.
And a 0.8 for the inverse of a negative
result of not getting cancer.
You multiply those together,
you get a normalized probability.
And if you now normalize by
the sum of those two things to
turn the statement to a probability,
you get 0.0009 over the sum of
those two things over here.
And this is 0.0056 for the chance
of having cancer, and 0.9943 for
the chance of being cancer-free.
And this adds up approximately to 1,
and therefore it's
a probability distribution.