I want to use a few
words of terminology.
This again is a Bayes network
of which the hidden variable
C causes the still stochastic
test outcomes T1 and T2.
And what's really important is that
we assume not just that T1 and
T2 are identically distributed.
It is the same 0.9 for
test one that I used for test two.
But we also assume that they
are conditionally independent.
We assumed that if God told us
whether we actually had cancer or not.
If you would ask with certainty
the breakup of variable C that knowing
anything about T1 would not help
us make a statement about T2.
But differently we assumed that
the probability of T2 given C and
T1 is the same as
the probability of T2 given C.
This is called conditional
independence which is given
the value of the cancer variable C,
if you do this for
fact than T2 would be independent of T1.
It's conditionally dependant because
independence only holds true
if we actually know C.
And it comes out of
this diagram over here.
If we look at this diagram,
if we knew the variable C over
here, then C separately causes T1 and
T2.
So as a result,
if we know C whatever over here,
it's kind of cut off, categorically
from what happens over here.
That causes these two variables
to be conditionally independent.
So conditional independence is
a really big thing for Bayes network.
Here's a Bayes network
where A causes B and C.
And for Bayes network of this structure,
we know that given A,
B and C are independent.
It's written as B condition
independent of C given A.
So here's a question, suppose we have
conditional independence between B and
C given A.
Would then imply, and that's my
question, that B and C are independent?
So, suppose we don't know A.
We don't know whether we have cancer,
for example.
Would that mean that the test results,
individually, yet still independent
of each other, even if we don't
know about the cancer situation?
Please answer yes or no.
[BLANK_AUDIO]