So, for this one,
we are going to apply total probability.
This thing over here is the same as
probability of test 2 to be positive,
which I am going to abbreviate
with a + 2 over here.
Condition on test 1 being positive and
me having cancer has probability
of me having cancer given
positive plus probability
of test 2 being positive
condition on positive and
me not having cancer,
times probability of me not having
cancer, given the test 1 is positive.
That's the same as
the total probability.
But now everything is
conditioned on + 1.
Take a moment to verify this.
Now here you can plug in the numbers.
We already calculated this one before,
which is approximately 0.043.
And this one over here is 1 minus this,
which is 0.957 approximately.
In this now exploits conditional
independence which is given that
knowledge of a first test gives me no
more information about the second test.
It only gives me information if C was
unknown as was the case over here.
So we can rewrite this thing over
here as follows P of plus 2,
given the cancer, I can drop the plus
1 and the same is true over here.
This is exploiting my
conditional independence.
I knew that P of plus 1 or
plus 2 condition on C is
the same as P of plus 2.
Condition of C and test 1.
I can now read those off my table here,
there's 0.9 times 0.043 plus 0.2,
which is 1 minus 0.8 over here,
times 0.957,
which gives me approximately 0.2301.
So that says if my first
test comes in positive,
I expect my second test to be
positive with the probably 0.2301.
That's an increase probability to the
default probability which we calculated
before, which is
probability of any test.
Test 2 coming as positive
before was to normalize or
Bayes rule which was 0.207.
So my first test has a 20%
chance of coming in positive,
my second test after seeing
a positive test has now an increased
probability of about 23%
of coming in positive.