And the answer is,
both of them are false.
We already saw that conditional
independence, as shown over here,
doesn't give us absolute independence.
So, for example, this is test
number one and test number two,
you might or might not have cancer.
Our first test gives us information
about whether you have cancer or not.
And as a result,
you've changed our prior probability for
the second test to come in positive.
That means conditional independence
does not imply absolute independence,
which renders this assumption,
here, false.
And as it also turns out that if
you have absolute independence,
things might not be
conditionally independent for
reasons that can't quite explain so
far but that we will learn about next.