For my next example, I will study
a different type of a Bayes network.
Before we've seen networks
of the following type,
where a single, hidden cause
caused two different measurements.
I now want to study a network that
looks just like the opposite.
We have two independent,
hidden causes, but
they get confounded within a single,
observational variable.
I would like to use
the example of happiness.
Suppose I can be happy or unhappy.
What makes me happy is
when the weather is sunny,
or if I get a raise at my job,
which means I make more money.
So let's call this sunny, let's call
this a raise and call this happiness.
Perhaps, the probability
of it being sunny is 0.7.
The probability of a raise is 0.01.
And I will tell you if the probability
of being happy is governed as false.
The probability of being happy given
that both of these things occur,
I got a raise and it's sunny, is 1.
The probability of being happy
given that it is not sunny and
I still got a raise, is 0.9.
The probability of being happy
given that it is sunny, but
I didn't give a raise, is 0.7.
And the probability of being happy,
given that it is neither sunny nor
did I get their raise, is 0.1.
This is a perfectly fine specification
of a probability distribution
where two causes affect the variable
down here, the happiness.
So I'd like you to calculate for
me the following questions.
The probability of a raise given that
it is sunny, according to this model.
Please enter your answer over here.