And let me talk about
a really interesting and
special instance of Bayes Net Reasoning
which is called explaining away.
And I'll first give you
the intuitive answer, and
then I wish you to
compute probabilities for
me that manifest the explain away
effect in Bayes Net of this type.
Explaining away means that,
if we know that we are happy,
then sunny weather can explain
away the cause of happiness.
If I then also know that it's sunny,
it becomes less likely
that I received a raise.
So let me put this differently, suppose
I'm a happy guy on a specific day, and
my wife asks me, Sebastian,
why are you so happy?
Is it sunny, or did you get a raise?
If she then looks outside and
sees it's sunny,
then she might explain to herself, well,
Sebastian is happy because it's sunny.
It makes it effectively,
less likely that he got a raise,
because I could already explain
this happiness by it being sunny.
If she looks outside and it's rainy,
it makes it more likely I got a raise,
because the weather can't
really explain my happiness.
In other words, if you see a certain
effect that it could be caused
by multiple causes,
seeing one of those causes can explain
away any other potential cause
of this effect over here.
So let me put this in numbers, and
ask you the challenging question of
what's the probability of the raise
given I'm happy, and it's sunny?