The answer is approximately 0.0142.
And as an exercise in expanding
this term using Bayes' rule,
using total probability,
which I just do for you.
Using Bayes' rule,
you can transform this into P of H,
given R, S times P of R
given S over P of H given S.
You observe the position
independence of R and S,
to simplify this to just P of R.
And the denominator is expanded
by folding in R and not R.
You have (H | R,S) times
P(R) plus P(H|-RS)
times P(-R) which is total probability.
You can now read off the numbers
from the tables over here,
which gives us 1 times 0.01
divided by this expression is
the same as the expression over here
0.01 plus this thing over here.
Which we can find over here
to be 0.7 x this one over
here which is one minus
the value over here 0.99.
Which gives us approximately 0.0142