So this is a difficult question.
Let me compute an auxiliary label,
which is P of Happiness, that one is
expanded by looking at the different
conditions that can make us happy.
P of Happiness given S and
R, times P of S and
R, which is of course
the product of those two,
because independent plus P of Happiness.
Given not S R, probability of
not S R + P of H given S and
not R times the probability
of P of S and
not R plus the last case P
of H given not S and not R.
So this just looks at the happiness and
all four combinations of the variables
that could lead to happiness.
And you can plug those straight in,
this one over here is 1.
And this one over here
is the product of S and
R which is 0.7 times 0.01.
And as you plug all of those in,
you get as a result,
0.5245, that's P(H).
Just take some time and do the math by
going through these different cases
using probability and
you get this result.
Now armed with this number,
the rest now becomes easy which is,
we can use base rule
to turn this around,
P(H given R) P(R) over P(H).
P(R) we know from over here,
the probability of a race is 0.01.
So the only thing we need to
compute now is P(H given R).
And again we applied sort of probability
let me just do this over here.
We can factor P(H given
R) as P(H given R,S) for
sunny times probability of
sunny plus P(H given R) and
not sunny times
the probability of not sunny.
And if you plug in the numbers for
this you get 1
times 0.7 + 0.9 times 0.3
that happens to be 0.97.
So if you now plug this all back
into this equation over here,
we get 0.97 times 0.01 / 0.5245.
This gives us approximately,
as a correct answer, 0.0185.