And if you got this right,
I will be deeply impressed of
the fact you got this right.
My happiness is well explained
by the fact that sunny.
So if someone observes you to
be happy and asks the question,
is this because Sebastian
got a raise at work?
Well If you know it's sunny and
this is a fairly good explanation for
me being happy.
You don't have to assume I got a raise.
If you don't know about the weather,
then obviously the chances are higher
that the raise caused my happiness.
And therefore this number
goes up from 0.014 to 0.018.
Let me ask you one final
question in this next quiz which
is the probability of a race given
that I look happy and it's not sunny.
This is the most extreme case for
making a raise likely because
I am a happy guy and it's definitely
not caused by the weather.
So it could be just random or
it could be caused by the raise.
So please calculate this number for
me and enter it into this box.