Now the answer follows the exact
same scheme as before,
with S being replaced by not S.
So this should be an easier question for
you to answer, P of R given H,
and not S, can be inverted by
base rule to be as follows.
Once we apply base rule,
as indicated over here,
where we sort H to the left side and
R to the right side,
you can observe that this value over
here can be readily found in the table.
It's actually the 0.9 over there.
This value over here,
the Bayes is independent of the data
Bayes network, so it's just 0.01.
And as before, we apply total
probability, the expression over here.
And we obtain of this
quotient over here,
that these two expressions are the same.
P of H given not S not R.
R is the value over here.
And the 0.99 is the compliment
of probability of R,
taken from over here and
that ends up to be 0.0833.
This will be the right answer.