It's really interesting to compare
this to the situation over here.
In both cases, I'm happy,
as shown over here.
And I asked the same question,
which is whether I got a raise at work,
this R over here.
But in one case,
I observe that the weather is sunny and
in the other one isn't.
And look what it does to my probability
of having received a raise.
The sunniness perfectly
well explains my happiness.
And my probability of
having received a raise
ends up to be a mere 1.4%, or 0.014.
However, if my wife observes it to
be not sunny, then it is much more
likely that the cause of my happiness
is related to a raise at work.
And now the probability is 8.3%,
which is significantly
higher than the 1.4% before.
Now, this is a Bayes'
network of which S and
R are independent, but
H adds a dependence between S and R.
Let me talk about this in a little
bit more detail on the next paper.
So here's a