The answer is A, 0.7445.
Even though the base net is simple the
answer will require a bit more work than
many of our challenge questions.
To be clear we'll be using capital
letters to indicate our variables.
We're using low case letters to
indicate when that variable is true,
or a non in front of it it to
indicate when its not true.
To solve this problem we have to
determine the ratio of times o2
is true given o1 is true,
to all situations where just o1 is true.
In other words, we sum over all possible
graduation situations, where o2 and
o1 are true for the numerator.
Which is simply,
the probability of o1 being true,
o2 being true and graduation being true.
Plus the probably of o1 being true, o2
being true and graduation being false.
And we're going to
normalize by this number,
plus the situation where o2 is negative.
And that is the probably of o1, not o2,
and g, plus the probably of o1,
not 02, and not g.
Looking at the first part of the
numerator, probability of o1, o2, and
g, that is simply
the probability of o1 given g,
times the probability of o2 given g,
times the probability of g.
And we can just read this off
the base network over here.
The first number,
the probability of o1 given g is 0.05.
Probability of o2 given g is just 0.75.
And the probability of g is just 0.9.
We multiply that out and it's 0.3375.
Next we'll consider the second
part of the numerator,
the probability of o1, o2, and not g.
Well that's simply the probability
of 01 given not g,
the probability of 02 given not g,
and the probability of not g.
And again we'll just read off our chart.
It's 0.05 for
a probability of o1 given not g,
0.25, which is a probability
of 02 given not g.
And then the probability of not g,
which is just the compliment of this,
which is 0.1.
That comes out to be 0.00125.
Now we'll consider the last
two parts of the equation.
We already have these
two from our numerator.
So now we need to look at
probability of o1, not o2, and g,
which is just equal to probability of o1
given g, probability of not o2 given g,
and probability of g.
Again, we can just read these
numbers off our base net.
It comes up to be 0.1125.
The final one probability,
of o1, not o2 and not g.
Again we just use the same equations and
we get 0.00375.
Now we can take all these
numbers we have just calculated,
put it into our equation, and
do the substitution and get our answer.
Doing the simple math
we end up with 0.7445,
which is what we were hoping for.
We calculated this answer by summing up
the results for all relevant situations.
But we can also do
inference by sampling,
which can handle much bigger networks.
Please be on the lookout for
all the different ways we can
do inference invasion networks.