And the answer to this one
is really interesting.
A is clearly not independent of
E because through C we can see
an influence of A to E.
Given B that doesn't change.
A still influences C
despite the fact we know B.
However if we know C,
the influence is cut off.
There is no way A can
influence E if we know C.
A is clearly independent of B.
They're different entry variables,
they have no incoming Rs.
&gt;&gt; But here is the caveat,
given C, A and B become dependent.
&gt;&gt; So whereas initially A and
B were independent,
if you give C they become dependent.
And the reason why they become
dependent we've studied before is
the Explain away effect.
If we know for example C to be true,
then knowledge of A will substantially
affect what we believe about B.
If there is two joint causes for C and
we happen to know A is true,
we will discredit cause B.
If we happen to know A is false we'll
increase our belief for the cause B.
There was an effect we studied
extensively in the happiness example I
gave you before.
The interesting thing here is you're
facing a situation where knowledge of
a variable C renders previously
independent variables dependent.