And the answer is yes.
F is independent of A. Well defined by our rules of the separation is
that F is dependent on D and A is dependent on D. But,
if you don't know D, you can't govern any dependency between A and F at all.
Now, if you do know D,
then F and A become dependent.
And the reason is B and E are dependent given D. And we can
transform this back into the dependency of A
and F because B and A are dependent, and E and F are dependent.
There's an active path between A and F,
which goes across here, and here,
because D is known.
Now if you know G, the same thing is true because G gives us knowledge about
D and D can be applied back to this path over here.
However, if you know H,
that's not the case.
So, H might tell us something about G,
but it doesn't tell us anything about D, and therefore,
we have no reason to close the path
between A and F. The path between A and F is still passive,
even though we have knowledge of H.