So we want to draw Bayes rule rapidly.
We have a situation where we
have an internal variable A,
like whether or not we have cancer.
But we can't sense A,
instead we have a second variable
called B, which is our test.
And B is observable, but A isn't.
This is a classical
example of a Base network.
The base network is composed
of two variables A and B.
We know the prior probability for A and
we know the conditional
A causes B whether or
not the cancer causes the test
result to be positive or not.
Although with some randomness involved.
So we know about the probability of
B given the different values for A.
And what we care about in this specific
instance is called diagnostic reasoning.
Which is inverse of
the causal reasoning.
Probability of A given B, or similarly,
probability of A given off B.
This is our very first Bayes Network and
the graphical representation
of drawn two variables, A and
B, connected with an arrow.
Because from A to B is a graphical
representation of distribution of two
variables that specified the structure
of a and this is a probability.
And has a conditional
probability which is normal.
Now I do have a quick quiz for you.
How many parameters does it
take to specify the entire
joint probability between A and
B or the entire Bayes Network?
I'm not looking for
a structural parameters.
We look to the graph over here,
just looking for
the numerical parameters of
the underlying probabilities.