The reason why I gave you all this
is because I wanted to apply it now
to a slightly more complicated problem,
which is the two test cancer example.
In this example, we, again,
might have our unobservable cancer c,
but now we're running two tests,
test one and test two.
As before,
the prior probability of cancer is 0.01.
The probability of receiving a positive
test result for either test is 0.9.
Probability of getting a negative
result, keeping them cancer free is 0.8.
And from those we were able to
compute all the other properties.
I'm just going to write
them down over here.
So take a moment to just write my notes.
Now let's assume both of my
tests come back positive.
So T1 = +, and T2 = +.
What's the probability of cancer now,
written in short form P(C|++)?
I want you to tell me what that is.
And this is a non trivial question.