So the correct answer is 0.1698
approximately.
And to compute this,
I used the trick I've shown you before.
Let me write down the running count for
cancer, and
for not cancer, as I integrate
the various multiplications in base row.
My prior for cancer was 0.01,
and for non-cancer was 0.99.
Then I get my first +, and
the probability of a plus given
that we have cancer is 0.9.
And the same for lung cancer is 0.2.
So according to
the non-normalized base rule,
I now multiply these two things
together to get my non-normalized
probability of having
cancer given the plus.
Since multiplication is commutative,
I can do the same thing again with
my second test result, 0.9, 0.2.
And I multiply all of these three things
together to get my non normalized
probability, P prime,
to be the following.
0.0081 if you multiply
those things together.
And 0.0396 if you multiply
these guys together.
And these are not a probability.
If we add those for
the two complementary,
with cancer, non cancer, I get 0.0477.
However, I now divide.
That is, I normalize those non
normalized probabilities over
here by this factor over here.
I actually get the correct
posterior probability.
P(C) given ++.
And they look as follows,
approximately 0.1698 and
approximately 0.8301.